Privacy Policy
==============

Last updated: September 25, 2018

Privacy Policy
==============

This Privacy Policy discloses how we collect, use, and store the information we obtain from users of HoffmanAcademy.com

We are committed to protecting your privacy and the security of your Personally Identifiable Information (PII). PII is information that can be used to identify you personally online. Examples of PII are your full name and your email address.

We collect information that is necessary in creating an account and using our services, and you can modify that information in our database at anytime. See our [Terms of Service](https://app.hoffmanacademy.com/terms-of-service/) for instructions if you would like to have your PII removed from our database.

We never sell your information to third parties or use third party services to show you ads on our website.

Account Information
-------------------

When you create a Hoffman Academy account, we collect your first name and your email address.

We use this information in two ways:

To set up your Hoffman Academy account:  
Your Hoffman Academy account creation requires personal information. The information is used to uniquely identify you at log in so you can access your lesson progress and purchases.

To send you emails:  
Hoffman Academy uses MailChimp, a third party email service. Your information is collected and used for the purpose of enabling Hoffman Academy to improve your Hoffman Academy experience by sending our monthly email newsletter and sales notifications to you. MailChimp does not share your information with any other entities, nor does it use the information to contact you in any way. See MailChimp’s privacy policy here.

If you decide you no longer want to receive emails from Hoffman Academy, you can have them stopped at any time. See our [Terms of Service](https://app.hoffmanacademy.com/terms-of-service/) for instructions on how to be removed from our mailing lists.

All information you enter on our website is safely encrypted using Secure Socket Layer (SSL). Only our administrators have access to the PII we collect.

The PII We Collect and Where It’s Stored
----------------------------------------

* Mailchimp – on MC servers. Email, name, number of students, subscription status, usage statistics, and email preferences. Relevant use: To enable us to send relevant emails to our users.
* Mandrill – on Mandrill servers. Name, email. Relevant use: To enable us to send transactional emails (gift codes and payment reminders).
* AWS RDS – Amazon Relational Database service – on AWS RDS hardware. Relevant use: To store user account data and usage statistics.
* Stripe – on Stripe servers. Email, payment information (name, credit card number), first name of each student on Premium accounts. Relevant use: Stripe is our payment processor.
* Profitwell – on Profitwell servers. Email, payment information (name, credit card information), first name of each student on Premium accounts. Relevant use: Profitwell organizes our financial, usage, and attribution data.
* PayPal – on PayPal servers. Email address, name, mailing address, credit card number. Relevant use: PayPal is our payment processor.
* Hoffman Academy Logging Server – stores site usage information. Email address, IP address, first name of each student. Relevant use: performance optimization, error analysis, site usage.
* Hoffman Academy support email (from contact form) – browser user agent string, IP address, subscription status. Relevant use: To help expedite customer service requests.
* Amazon SMS – stored on Amazon servers. Name, email address. Relevant use: To send transactional emails.
* Amazon web services – stored on Amazon hardware. Logs IP address, page requests. Relevant use: To help us understand site usage
* Ipdata.co – We send IP addresses to Ipdata.co to look up location to provide compliant cookie consent. Relevant use: Compliance with cookie consent laws.
* Zendesk – on Zendesk servers. Zendesk collects the data you choose to send to us through the Zendesk contact form. This includes email address, name, and content of message. Relevant use: Zendesk is our customer service and engagement platform.

See our [Terms of Service](https://app.hoffmanacademy.com/terms-of-service/) for more on Hoffman Academy accounts.

Cookies
-------

We use cookies on our website. A cookie is a small file that we or our service providers transfer to your computer’s hard drive in order to remember your browser and to store certain information.

Cookies allow us to respond to you as an individual and they enable us to remember you each time you visit our site. Cookies make it possible for your login to be remembered (that way you don’t have to enter the information upon each visit to our site).

You can use Hoffman Academy without cookies (by disabling them in your browser), but your experience using the site will be less than optimal. See our full [Cookie Policy](#cookie-policy) for more information.

Google Analytics
----------------

We use Google Analytics to collect information to tell us about your interaction with HoffmanAcademy.com. The information includes your country of residence, language, and the kind of browser and device you’re using. Additionally, Google Analytics shows us how you spend your time on HoffmanAcademy.com.

Financial Transactions
----------------------

When you make a purchase on our website, you have the choice of making a secure payment via payment processor Stripe or through PayPal. These third party services handle your financial information in the most secure way possible. Hoffman Academy does not collect or store your payment information. More information on Stripe payments can be found [here](https://stripe.com/privacy). More information on PayPal payments can be found [here](https://www.paypal.com/privacy).

Hoffman Academy Website/Blog and WordPress
------------------------------------------

To create our website and blog we rely on WordPress, a third party content management system. More information on WordPress’ privacy policy can be found [here](https://wordpress.org/about/privacy/).

Third Party Links
-----------------

We occasionally post links to third party products or services on our website or blog. For example, we link to relevant products on amazon.com. These third parties have independent privacy policies that do not fall under Hoffman Academy’s responsibility. If you have comments or concerns about our third party links, please contact us: [support@hoffmanacademy.com](mailto:support@hoffmanacademy.com)

We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.

Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)
------------------------------------------------

Hoffman Academy strives to be fully compliant with COPPA regulations.

We do not knowingly collect any PII from any individual under the age of 13. All visitors, including children under the age of 13, are able to visit our website and access our video lessons, blog, and music learning materials a guest. If you believe your child has shared any PII with us without your consent, please notify us and we’ll promptly remove it from our database.

Fair Information Practices
--------------------------

We are committed to keeping your PII as secure as possible. Should a data breach occur, we will notify you by email and by posting a notice on our website within 72 hours of discovery of the breach.

Policy Updates
--------------

Our Policies, including our Cookie Policy, are subject to changes and updates. We may need to change this policy from time to time to comply with new regulations or to reflect changes in our website or in the third party service providers we use. When we make changes to this policy we may notify you via email and will post the date of the most recent change at the top of this document.

Contact Information
-------------------

Hoffman Academy  
12660 NW Cornell Rd  
Portland, OR 97229

* * *

Cookie Policy
=============

Hoffman Academy (“us”, “we”, or “our”) uses cookies on the https://app.hoffmanacademy.com website (the “Site”). By using the Site, you consent to the use of cookies.

Our Cookies Policy explains what cookies are, how we use cookies, how third-parties we may partner with may use cookies on the Site, your choices regarding cookies and further information about cookies.

What are Cookies?
-----------------

Cookies are small pieces of text sent to your web browser by a website you visit. A cookie file is stored in your web browser and allows the Site or a third-party to recognize you and make your next visit easier and the Site more useful to you.

Cookies can be “persistent” or “session” cookies. Persistent cookies remain on your personal computer or mobile device when you go offline, while session cookies are deleted as soon as you close your web browser.

How Hoffman Academy Uses Cookies
--------------------------------

When you use and access the Site, we may place a number of cookies files in your web browser.

We use cookies for the following purposes:

* To enable certain functions of the Site
* To provide analytics
* To store your preferences

We use both session and persistent cookies on the Site and we use different types of cookies to run the Site:

* Essential cookies. We may use cookies to remember information that changes the way the Site behaves or looks, such as a user’s language preference on the Site.
* Accounts-related cookies. We may use accounts-related cookies to authenticate users and prevent fraudulent use of user accounts. We may use these cookies to remember information that changes the way the Site behaves or looks, such as the “remember me” functionality.
* Analytics cookies. We may use analytics cookies to track information how the Site is used so that we can make improvements. We may also use analytics cookies to test new advertisements, pages, features or new functionality of the Site to see how our users react to them.

Third Party Cookies
-------------------

In addition to our own cookies, we may also use various third-party cookies to report usage statistics of the Service. We do not control the operation of third-party cookies.

Our partners also collect data and use cookies for ad personalization and measurement. This information may be transferred outside of the country from which you are accessing this website. You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them below.

Third-party cookies which may be set on the Site include:

### Google Analytics

Google Analytics allows us to collect data about website usage. Google will not associate the IP address with any other data recorded by Google. The Google Privacy Policy can be viewed [here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

### Facebook

We use the Facebook Pixel to provide social media features and to analyze traffic to the site. We also share information about your use of our site. This allows us to measure ad conversions and retarget advertisements on Facebook. You can find more information on this [here](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/) and in our [privacy policy](#top).

### Unbounce

We use Unbounce to create some of the pages on our site. Unbounce writes cookies to track usage, store user preferences, improve conversions, and provide us with analytics to improve the performance of our pages.

### Pinterest

We track the performance of our pins on Pinterest using cookies. We also share information about your use of our site. This allows us to measure conversions. You can find more information on this [here](https://policy.pinterest.com/en/cookies) and in our [privacy policy](#top).

### YouTube

Our lessons are embedded on YouTube. We use cookies to track video viewing statistics and we use cookies to personalize ads on the Google Display Network.

Your Cookie Choices
-------------------

If you’d like to delete cookies or instruct your web browser to delete or refuse cookies, please visit the help pages of your web browser. To update your cookie preferences click here.

Please note, however, that if you delete cookies or refuse to accept them, you might not be able to use all of the features we offer, you may not be able to store your preferences, and some of our pages might not display properly. Note: If you are a Premium user, disabling all cookies will prevent you from accessing any Premium materials on our site.

* For the Chrome web browser, please visit this page from Google: [https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/32050](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/32050)
* For the Internet Explorer web browser, please visit this page from Microsoft: [http://support.microsoft.com/kb/278835](http://support.microsoft.com/kb/278835)
* For the Firefox web browser, please visit this page from Mozilla: [https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored)
* For the Safari web browser, please visit this page from Apple: [https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=en\_US](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=en_US)
* For any other web browser, please visit your web browser’s official web pages.

You can learn more about cookies at the following third-party websites:

* AllAboutCookies: [http://www.allaboutcookies.org/](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)
* Network Advertising Initiative: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)

Hoffman Academy © 2024
